# **Dmytro Dvornichenko**

Product Design Lead

- Website
- Linkedin
- E-mail

17 years of experience in UX and UI design for SaaS and consumer apps.

Clients: HPE, Ryanair, Fujifilm, Kantar, Plarium, CPPIB, WCG, FUIB, Rozetka.

3+ years of experience as a design manager in a highly distributed design team.

Located in a safe place in **Kyiv**, **UA**, with 24/7 internet access and electricity supply. Ready to work in time zones from EST to GMT+4.

#### Education

## **B.S., Telecommunications Engineer**

Kharkiv National University of Radio Electronics (KNURE), 2013, Ukraine

# Junior Specialist, Computer systems and networks service

Kharkiv Patent Computer College, 2009, Ukraine

# Mentoring & Publications

Projector, Product Design, 2022 Projector, UX Design, 2022 Projector, Mentoring, 2021 Projector, Design Systems, 2021 KyivUX, Mentoring, 2021 Telegraf, Design Systems, 2021

#### Skills

Product Vision, Product Strategy,
Design Systems, Cross-functional
Leadership, Product Design, Strategic
Planning, Design Operations,
Stakeholder Management,
Problem-Solving, Design workshops,
Collaboration, Creativity, Adaptability,

# **Work Experience**

### Lead Product Designer, Web

04/2024 - Present

Datrics | USA (Remote)

Leading product design for a breakthrough AI Data Analyst platform.

- Designed 15+ major features (playground, setup flow), resulting in successfully signed contracts and positive customer feedback on UX.
- Refreshed company branding with new logo, colors, social assets and graphics to boost market differentiation.
- Collaborated with Sales on improvements for assets, increasing conversion rates across leads and customers.

### Lead Product Designer, Web

02/2023 - 03/2024

Cinderblock | USA (Remote)

Led product design of job management SaaS for contractors.

- Led design system development core principles, accessibility, UI kit and iterative improvements based on user needs
- Collaborated with the front-end team to maintain design accuracy and consistency during component implementation and adoption phase.
- Redesigned most of the core app features, leading to improved time-of-completion of crucial user flows and positive user feedback.

# Founding Product Designer, Web

05/2022 - 01/2023

WOMBI | UK (Remote)

Led product design for web3 marketing analytics platform resulting in successful MVP launch within 6 months.

- Created a consistent design system for the application, resulting in an organized and predictable user experience throughout the platform.
- Created a unique brand identity, including a set of AI-generated wombat mascots and a landing page, that helped differentiate the product in the market.
- Led market research initiative that improved customer targeting, resulting in higher community engagement and sales growth.

# Design Technology Lead, CEE

04/2019 - 04/2022

GlobalLogic | Ukraine (Remote)

Managed a team of 30+ designers across CEE region, supporting their expertise growth and solving project-related issues, implementing company-wide design strategy, integrating Design Thinking to the SDLC, and consulting on design processes for multiple projects.

 Started transition to an updated design management workflow, simplifying hiring, staffing, and performance review activities for 200+ designers and managers across the organization. Strategic Thinking, Critical Thinking, Self-Motivation, Mentorship, Design Thinking, User Research, User Interviews, Journey Mapping, Ideation, Concept Development, Prototyping, Interaction Design, Information Architecture, Responsive Design, Mobile Design, Web Design, Visual Design, Identity, Motion Design, Video Design, Generative Art, Typography, Testing, Qualitative Research, A/B Testing & Analytics, Usability Testing, Design Leadership, Design Management, Project Management, Agile, Team Management, OKRs, Goal Setting, Business Impact Measurement, Remote Team Leadership, Design Ethics, Accessibility, Design QA, Design Documentation, Budgeting

#### **Tools**

Figma, HTML5/CSS3,
JavaScript/TypeScript, React, CSS
Animations, GLSL Shaders, p5.js
Replit, Cursor, GitHub Copilot, Chrome
DevTools, Framer, Rive, Webflow, Git,
GitHub, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe
Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Midjourney,
Principle, Microsoft Office, Google
Workspace, Keynote, Google Analytics,
Mixpanel

- Secured new clients and boosted revenue by actively participating in sales activities like presenting Design Expertise, creating concepts, negotiating deals, briefing clients, and leading design kick-off activities.
- Improved Design Delivery in 5+ project teams by facilitating design review sessions, conducting design audits, and reporting to clients and Delivery Directors, leading to increased client demand for team services and enhanced team collaboration.
- Completed individual development plans with 10+ designers by developing clear goals and action plans, providing guidance and support, and fostering a productive working environment.

### Lead UX Designer, Web and Mobile

04/2018 - 04/2019

GlobalLogic | Canada (Remote)

As a key member of Method team, led the creation of a concept UI design approach for a Portfolio Management platform, resulting in a multi-year software engineering contract with a top-tier investment fund. Designed 5 major features for the Clinical Research Platform, revamped the internal design process, and introduced client engagement activities, resulting in an additional contract, team expansion, and tighter collaboration of the design team with software engineering units.

### **Product Designer, Mobile**

05/2017 - 04/2018

MOSST | Ukraine

Led the research, prototyping, and redesign of the mPOS reader app (iOS, Android).

### **Product Designer, Web**

05/2014 - 04/2018

Plarium | Ukraine

Designed numerous browser game features played by 250M+ users across 150 countries, reducing overall drop-offs and increasing retention and engagement.

# **UX Designer, Web**

02/2013 - 05/2014

EPAM | Ireland, USA (remote)

Led the redesign of the check-in user interface for Ryanair, resulting in an increase in business metrics and customer satisfaction rate. Led design research, prototyping, and interaction design for core user interfaces of Kantar Media web & media analytics service.

### **UX Designer, Mobile**

01/2011 - 02/2013

Turumburum | Ukraine

Implemented full product design cycle for banking apps (web, iPhone, iPad, Android) of FUIB / ΠУΜБ bank (#8 bank in Ukraine in 2011).

### **UI Designer, Web**

01/2008 - 09/2008

Meta.UA | Ukraine

Prototyped and designed websites, branding & promotional materials for small e-commerce stores and businesses in Ukraine.